<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/esr2html.xsl"?>

<ESR xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/esr" name="Operating System Fundamentals">
  
	<intro>
		<esrtitle>General-Purpose Computing Platform Protection Profile</esrtitle>
		<maintainer>NIAP</maintainer>
		<identifier>42</identifier>
		<version>0.2</version>
		<status>draft</status>
		<issuedate>15 September 2020</issuedate>
		<approver/>
		<supercedes/>
	</intro>

	<section title="Background and Purpose" id="purpose">
		This document describes the high-level security requirements
		to be met by general-purpose computing platforms. The resulting
		Protection Profile will define baseline security functionality
		with additional security options. <br/><br/>

		A platform is a collection of hardware devices and firmware that
		provide the functional capabilities and services needed by tenant
		software. Such devices typically include embedded controllers, trusted
		platform modules, management controllers, host processors, network
		interface controllers, graphics processing units, flash memory,
		storage controllers, storage devices, boot firmware, runtime firmware,
		human interface devices, and a power supply.
	</section>
	
	<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
	  	A general-purpose computing platform is a hardware device that it capable
		of hosting more than one different operating system, virtualization system,
		or bare-metal application. Typical platform implementations include--but are not
		limited to--servers, PC clients, laptops, and tablets.
	</section>

	<section title="Resources to be protected" id="resourcesprotected">
		The platform has three major security responsibilities:
		<ul>
			<li>ensuring the integrity of its own firmware</li>
			<li>ensuring that it is resilient</li>
			<li>providing security services to tenant workloads</li>
		</ul><br/><br/>

		These responsibilities manifest as protecting: 
		<ul>
			<li>Platform firmware</li>
			<li>Platform firmware updates</li>
			<li>Tenant initialization (boot)</li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Attacker access" id="attackeraccess"> 
		The attackers are assumed to have compromised the tenant software such that
		malicious code can run remotely or automatically to attack the platform. The attackers
		are assumed to have network access to the platform such that they can launch remote attacks.
	</section>
	
	<section title="Essential Security Requirements" id="requirements">
		
		The following are the essential security requirements that are expected to be enforced by any GPCP TOE:<br/><br/>
		<ol>
			<li>Platform Integrity—Roots of Trust<br/><br/>
			Roots of trust are security primitives that provide a set of trusted, security-critical
			functions. They must always behave in an expected manner because their misbehavior cannot
			be detected.<br/><br/>
			A platform must implement the following roots of trust:
			<ol>
				<li>Root of Trust for Storage (RTS) – provides protected repository and protected interface for storing keying material.</li>
				<li>Root of Trust for Verification (RTV) – provides protected engine and interface to verify digital signatures associated 
					with firmware and to create assertions based on the results.</li>
				<li>Root of Trust for Integrity (RTI) – provides protected storage, integrity protection, and a protected interface to store
					and manage assertions.</li>
				<li>Root of Trust for Reporting (RTR) – provides a protected environment and interface to manage identities and sign assertions.</li>
				<li>Root of Trust for Measurement (RTM) – provides measurement used by assertions protected via the RTI and attested to with the RTR.</li>
			</ol>
			</li>
		<li>Platform Resilience—Protect, Detect, Recover<br/><br/>
		The platform must support the following security capabilities to ensure its own integrity:
			<ol>
				<li>Protection of Platform Integrity:
					<ol>
						<li>Protect Platform Firmware – The platform firmware can be modified only through an authorized mechanism.</li>
						<li>Authenticated Update – The platform firmware updates must be authenticated via a root of trust before they are applied.</li>
					</ol>
				</li>
				<li>Detection of Platform Integrity
					<ol>
						<li>Hardware Integrity – The platform must be able to detect changes in its hardware configuration. </li>
						<li>Firmware Integrity. – The platform must be able to detect changes to its firmware made outside of an
							authenticated update mechanism.</li> 
					</ol>
				</li>
				<li>Platform Recovery
					<ol>
						<li>The platform must be capable of restoring platform firmware and critical data that has been corrupted or
							changed from its authorized state.</li>
					</ol>
				</li>
			</ol>
		</li>
		<li>Security Services for Tenant Software<br/><br/>
		The platform must provide the following security services to tenant software:
			<ol>
				<li>Protected Storage – The platform must support a mechanism for protecting the confidentiality and integrity of sensitive
					data while at rest.</li>
				<li>Assured Erase – The platform must provide a mechanism for assured erasure of unencrypted sensitive data at rest.</li>
				<li>Isolation – The platform must provide a mechanism that can be leveraged by tenant software to support the isolation of
					different computing contexts. This could be something as simple as processor support for process isolation, processor
					support for virtualization, or platform support for application isolation.</li>
				<li>Platform Identity – The platform must have a unique identity for purposes of platform authentication.</li>
				<li>Cryptographic Services – The hardware platform may implement cryptographic services in hardware. This could include
					RNGs, entropy sources, and cryptographic functions implemented in hardware.</li>
				<li>Management Services – Baseboard Management Controller (BMC)/Management Engine (ME) – The platform may provide out-of-band
					management services for tenant software.</li>
			</ol>
		</li>
		</ol>
	</section>

	<section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
		It is assumed that an attacker has no access to the physical device, but has
		access to the tenant workload and to tenant workload networks. 
	</section>

	<section title="Outside the TOE's Scope" id="outsidescope">
		This section has been intentionally left blank.
	</section>
</ESR>
